alphasights.com 2019-05-09

# AlphaSights

AlphaSights Ltd., its subsidiaries and affiliates (“AlphaSights”, “we”, “us”, “our”) respect your privacy and are committed to protecting your personal data. This Privacy & Cookie Policy will inform you how we look after your personal data when you visit our website(s) (regardless of where you visit from) and tell you about your privacy rights and how the law protects you.

It is important that you read this Privacy & Cookie Policy together with any other privacy notice or fair processing notice we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data. This Privacy & Cookie Policy supplements the other notices and is not intended to override them.

Our website(s) are not intended for children and we do not knowingly collect data relating to children.

## 1\. IMPORTANT INFORMATION AND WHO WE ARE 

AlphaSights is made up of different legal entities, details of which (including all necessary contact details) can be found here. AlphaSights Ltd. is the controller and responsible for our website(s) but this Privacy & Cookie Policy is issued on behalf of our whole corporate group.

### CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY & COOKIE POLICY AND YOUR DUTY TO INFORM US OF CHANGES 

We may change this Privacy & Cookie Policy from time to time without notice and any such changes will take effect from the time the revised version is available on our website(s). We therefore ask that you bookmark and periodically review this page to ensure your understanding of, and agreement with, the latest version of this Privacy and Cookie Policy.

### THIRD-PARTY LINKS

Our website(s) may include links to or functionality from third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit.

## 2\. THE DATA WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU 

Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together follows:

  * Identity Data, including first name, maiden name, last name, username or similar identifier, title, and gender.
  * Contact Data, including your address(es), email address(es) and telephone number(s).
  * Financial Data (if we pay you anything), including bank account details.
  * Transaction Data, including interactions you may have had with us.
  * Technical Data, including internet protocol (IP) address, login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access our website(s).
  * Profile Data, including your CV, professional background and career history.
  * Usage Data, including information about how you use our website, products and services.
  * Marketing and Communications Data, including your preferences in receiving marketing from us and third parties and your communication preferences.

We may also collect, use and share aggregated data such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated data may be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data does not directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific website feature. However, if we combine or connect aggregated data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this Privacy & Cookie Policy.

We do not intend to collect the following special categories of personal data about you: your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data.

### IF YOU FAIL TO PROVIDE PERSONAL DATA

Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you. In this case, we may cancel a service you receive from us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time.

## 3\. HOW IS YOUR PERSONAL DATA COLLECTED? 

We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:

  * Direct interactions. You may give us your Identity, Contact and Financial Data by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email or otherwise. 
  * Automated technologies. As you interact with our website(s), we may automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies, server logs and other similar technologies. 
  * Third parties or publicly available sources. We may receive personal data about you from various third parties and public sources such as Technical Data from analytics, technology and hosting providers, Identity and Contact Data from business networks, data brokers or aggregators and from publicly availably sources.

## 4\. HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA 

We only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

  * Where we need to perform a contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.
  * Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.
  * Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.
  * When you have expressly consented to us processing your personal data. Where consent is relied on, you have the right to withdraw it at any time by contacting us.

### PURPOSES FOR WHICH WE WILL USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA 

We have set out below a description of the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate.

Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please contact us if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below.

Purpose/Activity | Type of data  | Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest  
---|---|---  
To manage our relationship with you which will include: (a) interacting with you proactively and in response to requests from you. (b) Notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policy | (a) Identity (b) Contact (c) Profile (d) Financial (e) Marketing and Communications | (a) Performance of a contract with you (b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation (c) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our products/services) (d) Consent, where applicable  
To administer and protect our business and our website(s) (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data) | (a) Identity (b) Contact (c) Technical | (a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise) (b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
To deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you and measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you |  (a) Identity (b) Contact (c) Profile (d) Usage (e) Marketing and Communications (f) Technical | Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them, to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy)  
To use data analytics to improve our website, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences | (a) Technical (b) Usage | Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our products and services, to keep our website updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy)  
To make suggestions and recommendations to you about goods or services that may be of interest to you | (a) Identity (b) Contact (c) Technical (d) Usage (e) Profile | Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our products/services and grow our business)  
  
### OPTING OUT

You can ask us or third parties to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by contacting us. Opting out will not apply to personal data provided to us for other purposes.

### COOKIES

AlphaSights may send one or more cookies – text only strings of characters identifying a visitor's browser – when you visit our website(s). You can configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set. AlphaSights records every visit to its website(s) and logs web request and internet protocol address information. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of our website(s) may become inaccessible or not function properly.

### CHANGE OF PURPOSE

We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please contact us. If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.

Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.

##  5\. DISCLOSURES OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA 

We may have to share your personal data with third parties such as clients, suppliers, sub-contractors, data processors and any parties to whom we may sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this Privacy & Cookie Policy.

We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not consent to our third-party service providers using your personal data for their own purposes.

##  6\. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS 

We may share your personal data within the AlphaSights group and external third parties. This may involve transferring your data outside the European Economic Area (EEA). Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we endeavour to ensure, pursuant to our agreements with such third parties/group members, that a similar degree of protection is afforded to it as within the EEA. Please contact us if you want further information on the specific mechanism used by us when transferring your personal data out of the EEA.

## 7\. DATA SECURITY 

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They should only process your personal data on our instructions and be subject to a duty of confidentiality. We have also put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

##  8\. DATA RETENTION 

HOW LONG WILL YOU USE MY PERSONAL DATA FOR? 

We will only retain your personal data for as long as we believe necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, reporting or audit requirements. To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

Details of retention periods for different aspects of your personal data are available by contacting us.

## 9\. YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS 

Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data. These include rights:

To request access to your personal data (commonly known as a “data subject access request”). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.

To request correction of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.

To request erasure of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.

To object to processing of your personal data. This is where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.

To request restriction of processing of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the data’s accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.

To request the transfer of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.

To withdraw consent. This occurs at any time where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact us.

### NO FEE USUALLY REQUIRED 

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

### WHAT WE MAY NEED FROM YOU

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

### TIME LIMIT TO RESPOND 

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues (www.ico.org.uk). We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so please contact us here in the first instance.
